Guide to the Arthur Clarence Walworth Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1892-1949, 1976, 1979; Accession 1994-M-004; 2.50 linear feet linear feet (3 boxes)
  - Scrapbook of Yale printed material: programs, invitations, exam questions, newspaper clippings, photographs, memorabilia, and personal correspondence, 1893-1897, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Classbook of photographs of the Class of 1897
  - Wilson and His Peacemakers: American Diplomacy at the Paris Peace Conference of 1919
    - Parts I-V: drafts (Box 2)
    - Research materials
      - Microfilm (one reel), photocopies from the Ministère des Affaires Étrangères, Archives Diplomatiques, Sèrie A, Conditions de la Paix, 1914-1919, États-Unis (Box 2)
      - "Le Ultime Sedute dei quattro," Nuovi Ricordi: photocopies, undated (Box 2)
      - "Woodrow Wilson and the Military: The Case of General Tasker H. Bliss," by Thomas English, with accompanying correspondence, 1979 (Box 2)
  - America's Moment: 1918, or the Americans at Paris: 1918: American Diplomacy at the End of World War I
    - Draft, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Research materials, 1919-1949, undated (Box 3)
  - Letter from A. C. Walworth to R. Gordon Hoxie, editor of Presidential Studies Quarterly, re the role of Edward House at the Paris Peace Conference of 1919, 1993 August 4 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1959
    From Accession 1994-M-093
    Received from Ellen Ebersole, 1994 Jun 4
    - Butler, ______, 1959 (Box 3)
    - Hurst, Cecil, 1959 (Box 3)
    - Salter, ______, undated (Box 3)
    - Warrin, Frank L., 1964, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Webster, C., 1959 (Box 3)
  - "Paris Peace Conference Remembered," Nota Bene News from the Yale Library, 1994 spring (Box 3)
  - "Considerations on Woodrow Wilson and Edward M. House: An Essay Letter to the Editor," by Arthur C. Walworth, Presidential Studies Quarterly, 1994 winter (Box 3)
- Additional material, 1919, 1930, 1938-1994, undated; Accession 1995-M-091; 0.5; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1995 Jan
  Received from: Ellen Ebersole, 1994 Nov 23
  - Correspondence/topical files
    - Baker, Newton, 1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Baruch, Bernard, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Benham, Edith, 1943, 1961-1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bonsal, Philip, 1976, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bragdon, Henry, 1960, 1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Chiang, Yee, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Egerton, George, 1977, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - England: libraries and research facilities, Circa 1959-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hamilton, Guy, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Headlam-Morley, Agnes, 1959, 1968, 1974-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Monroe, Elizabeth, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Schmitt, Bernadotte, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Swope, H. B.: dispatches from Paris to The World, 1919 March 13-14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Yale University Library, 1957, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Black Ships off Japan: partial early draft, correspondence, printed material of BBC show, 1945-1978, 1985, 1994, undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - School Histories at War, by A. Walworth, with accompanying correspondence, printed material, 1930, 1938-1944, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Too Proud to Fight, by Patrick Devlin: A. Walworth's review, with accompanying correspondence, printed matter, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Additional material, Accession 1999-M-115
  - Cape Breton
    - Background, 1941, 1946-1947, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1942, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence
    - A-Z [general], 1938-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Kaspi, Andre, 1952, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Kennan, George, 1956-1960, 1974-1975, 1979-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - House-Paderewski Symposium
    - Correspondence, 1991-1992, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Notes, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Writings, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Presidential Studies Quarterly essay, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Seymour, Charles
    - Clippings, 1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1939, 1946, 1950-1963, 1965, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Woodrow Wilson [biography of Wilson]
    - Clippings, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
    - Interview Notes
      - A-Z [general], 1952, 1959-1961, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Family, 1948-1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence
      - Publication, 1958-1960, 1980, 1987-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Pulitzer Prize, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Northern Ireland [re: Wilson's heritage], 1965-1968, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Reviews, 1958-1960, 1969, 1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Recollections [of speech given by Lyndon Baines Johnson at a White House luncheon for scholars on April 30, 1964, and of Charles Seymour, president of Yale University], 1987 (Box 3)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
- Additional material, Accession 2005-M-027
  - Correspondence with Phyllis Lee Levin, 1989-2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reviews of Levin's writings, 1991, 1993, 1997-2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Roger Louis re Walworth manuscript, 1964 March 19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with staff of Yale-China Association [includes printed materials], 1923, 1970, 1991, 1999, 2000, 2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional material, 1989; Accession 2006-M-098
  This accession consists of a recording made on June 7, 1989, during which Arthur Walworth reads an account of his 1925 visit to the Republic of China to an unidentified audience at North Hill. Walworth recalls arriving in Ch'ang-sha, the capital of Hunan sheng (province), where he taught English at the Yale-in-China medical school. The account continues with descriptions of student protests and other revolutionary activities that rocked China as Nationalist and Communist forces clashed. The tape also includes Walworth's interactions with Christian missionaries in China; descriptions of Chinese leaders, such as Chiang Kai-shek and Mao Tse-tung; and Walworth's personal experiences and reflections on his trip.
  - Audio recording of Walworth's China travels, 1989; 1 (Box 1)